# **Atul Meshram**

# **Product Designer**

🕑 🛮 Bangalore, Karnataka - INDIA





# **Education**

- **Interaction Design Specialization** University of California, San Diego 9.9 Score | Jan, 2018 | Coursera
- **Master of Computer Applications** NIT Karnataka, Surathkal 8.5 CGPA | May, 2016
- **GNIIT Software Engineering** NTTT

Grade - A | Apr, 2013

- **Bachelor of Computer Applications** PRSU, Raipur 78.0% | Jun, 2011
- Class 12th (Senior Secondary Edu.) **CBSE - All India** 81.0% | May, 2007

### **Skills**

**Design Tools** 

InVision Studio Sketch Adobe XD Figma

FramerX Adobe After Effects **ProtoPie** Adobe Illustrator

Flinto Blender

**User Experience** 

User Research Motion Design Wireframing Visual Design Rapid Prototyping **Heuristic Evaluation** A/B Testing **Usability Testing** Interaction Design Comparative Analysis

**Programming** 

JavaScript (ES6) **ThreeJS** HTML5 **GSAP** CSS3 **VueJS** 

ReactJS

Leadership

**Project Planning** UX Strategy & Planning Team Coordination Training & Mentorship

# Summary

Product designer with 4+ years of user-centric design experience. I enjoy interacting with people, understand their expectations and displeasing experiences from the products, and use their insights to create simple and intuitive interfaces that have a high degree of usability. Interested in immersive design and extended reality-based emerging technologies.

# **Experience**

#### o9 Solutions

Bengaluru, IN

## **Senior Product Designer**

[ MAY, 2018 - Present ]

- Designed and prototyped, multiple widgets and features for web, mobile, and desktop applications varying from small, one-week prototypes that explored specific interactions to large-scale, multi-month projects targeted for the launch.
- Designed intuitive, interactive, and smart analytical visual interface for the AI-based smart supply-chain platform offering features like:

Natural Language Search, Rich Data Visualization, Real-Time Collaboration, Connected Excel, Mobile Experience, Integrated Email, Geo Map & Network, Online Meeting and Presentation, and Favorite Management.

Case Study: https://atulmeshram.github.io/o9-solutions.html

#### **Accolite Software**

Bengaluru, IN

#### **UX** Designer

[ JUL, 2016 - MAR, 2018 ]

Worked for various clients at client locations. Analyzed, prototyped, and delivered the designs as per client's design requirements.

#### [ NOV, 2017 - MAR, 2018 ] **Standard Chartered Banking App**

A mobile app for managing finances anytime anywhere.

Designed UI to offer UPI based transactions to facilitate safe, easy & instant digital payments.

Google Play Store: https://cutt.ly/ryNkoPX

#### FedEx FRMS iPad App

[ SEP 2017 - NOV 2017 ]

An iPad app for FedEx's Pilot Fatigue Management.

Analyzed existing web application and redesigned the workflow for the app.

Designed high-fidelity clickable prototypes, UI design assets distribution, application flow, animations, and design guide for the developers.

#### **BT Business App**

[ JUL 2016 - OCT 2017 ]

A business service mobile app for users offering with features to view bills, check accounts, test broadband speed, track orders, and faults.

User-research, analysis, and interpretation of customer needs, to create a pleasant user experience. Designed application flow, created wireframes and high-fidelity mock-ups.

Google Play Store: https://cutt.ly/8yNkbU2 **Apple App Store:** https://cutt.ly/kyNkRFY

